# Rasool Dezhkam

### **Software Developer**

Isfahan, Iran

Tel: +98 9132130422

Email: Dezhkam@yahoo.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rasooldezhkam

A Software Engineer with +10 years' experience who likes challenges and making the best effort on any project. Worked on many successful projects and collaborated with many technical teams. Seeks scalability and performance challenges in the career.

#### **SKILLS**

- PHP programming (Web Application, MVC)
- Laravel Framework.
- Backend, microservices, REST API, and Web API.
- Software design principles, SOLID, and Design patterns.
- Agile Methodologies such as Scrum and Kanban.
- System design and architecture patterns.
- Version control tools like Git, GitHub.
- Relational databases (MSSQL Server and MySQL)
- NoSQL databases (MongoDB)
- E-commerce platform such as Magento, Shopware6.
- IDE (PhpStorm, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse)
- Web Server: XAMPP.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## • Full Stack Developer at Safer(Jan 2018 – Present)

- ✓ The design of a mechanized software system for car technical inspection with automatic license plate recognition led to higher quality and 30% time savings.
- ✓ Developed a trucking bill of lading registration system as a desktop application that helped transport companies lessen paper consumption by 80% and ease the registration time and truck driver scheduling process. Eliminating the cost of transportation companies by 10%.
- ✓ Created an accounting system with the ability to connect to the cargo registration system, which led to a 20% time reduction.
- ✓ Prepared a mobile application for drivers to access the system, which saved 50% for drivers.
- ✓ Presented a mobile application for transport companies greatly facilitates their access to the system.
- ✓ Provided a mobile application for goods owners to access the system through mobile phones.
- ✓ Implemented the web-based system of the truck waybill registration system. There was a 5% cost savings for the transport companies.

✓ Integration of all transport companies into this web-based system, faced with a high-volume database and massive data. By optimization of SQL queries and tuning tables, system performance was improved and became 10 times faster.

### • Full Stack Developer at Phoenix(Sep 2014 – Dec 2017)

- ✓ Participated in creating a tender and auction system to control tenders and auction processes and eliminated 90% of paper correspondence.
- ✓ Designed a web-based contractor management system. Provided communication between the employer and contractors. That caused a 70% reduction in paper consumption and a 10% reduction in companies' correspondence costs.
- ✓ Led a team to complete a supplier management system that helped organizations to direct their supply chain effectively and decreased costs by 20%.
- ✓ Refactored the source code of the old automation system with the new one.

## • Junior Full Stack Developer at Behsan(May 2012 – Aug 2014)

- ✓ Founded a very flexible call center and implemented that in over 50 Organizations. Automated the internal telephone systems.
- ✓ Developed telephony applications for communication with various modems and phone-switching devices such as Panasonic PBX. Supported up to 64 external telephone lines.
- ✓ Achieved a Web-based Application as a user panel of our telephony system. Cut down time costs by 10%.
- ✓ Invented a flexible web-based shop with various products and executed for more than 20 companies.
- ✓ Launched many websites for 100 companies.

### **EDUCATION**

- Master's degree, Artificial Intelligence, Amirkabir University of Technology Tehran, Iran
- Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering, Yazd University Yazd, Iran

### **LANGUAGES**

- Persian (Native)
- English (Conversational)